SYED HASNAIN BUKHARI Profile-pio



FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT

LIFE SUKHUMVIT 48, FLOOR 24TH, 122 SUKHUMVIT RD, PHRA KHANONG BANGKOK KHLONG TOEI 10110

SYEDHASNAINBUKHARI01@H OTMAIL.COM

(+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/HAS NAIN-BUKHARI-30494184 🗗

IN/HASNAIN BUKHARI 🗗

HASNAIN BUKHARI 🗗

WEB DEVELOPMENT

EXPERT

HTML **JAVASCRIPT**

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE

ADVANCED

DESIGN-PATTERNS DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS SCALABILITY MAINTAINABILITY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

PROFICIENT

SUSTAINABILITY PORTABILITY **SCALABILITY** REASONABILITY

PROBLEM SOLVING

ADVANCED

COMPETITIVEPROGRAMMING **ABSTRACT**

DRAFT DOCUMENTATION **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

EXPERIENCE

AGODA

12/2021 - PRESENT

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the organization
- Build a mindset and culture of quality first; Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

STRATEGIC SYSTEM INTERNATIONAL

11/2019 - 12/2021

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Design and developed multiple major modules and provide technical support to web application as well mobile application. My responsibilities include:

- Building micro services oriented systems that enable integration with various external systems.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Optimizing and refactoring existing modules to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.
- Design and develop timesheets management module based on types of systems. User can track workings hours and working experience with different clients. User can upload paper timesheets as well.
- Implementation of Elastic search to enhance the performance and visualize
- Provide technical to mobile application
- Provide technical support and consultancy to other projects as well

CUREMD

09/2017 - 11/2019

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developed multiple major projects, as a full stack .NET developer as well as a software architect. My responsibilities include:

- Building highly scalable and robust, service-oriented systems that enable integration of our flagship product with various external information
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Providing technical and client support to various deployed products. Coordinate and plan inter and intra team activities.
- Restructure and refactor modules of existing products to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.

LOGIX INFINITY

06/2016 - 09/2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Worked as a software developer, specializing in web and desktop application development, mainly using the .NET stack along with other web technologies

PROFICIENT

DOCSIFY GITHUB MARP JOPLIN MERMAIDJS FORMSIO

COMMUNICATION

COMPETENT

FACE-2-FACE
EMAILS
PRESENTATIONS
CONFERENCE
BUY-IN TALKS
NEGOTIATIONS
LAYMAN CONVERSIONS

1:15

LANGUAGES

URDU (NATIVE SPEAKER) ENGLISH (FLUENT)

INTERESTS

HOME IMPROVEMENTS & ENGINEERING

Plumbing Electric-appliances Civil engineering

SOFTWARE BASED HOME SOLUTIONS

IoT Home-server plex raspberry-pi cups saned

WATCHING DOCUMENTARIES

Idiocracy Lord-of-the-rings movies documentaries (Angular, Ionic and JavaScript). It gave me a chance to work on an array of diverse projects, offering me a great learning experience and exposure. I've developed web-based software using ASP.NET (MVC, WEB API, .NetCore), Angular/Ionic and SOI Server

EDUCATION

FAST - NUCES

06/2006 - 07/2010

BACHELOR COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Digital Logic Design
- Assembly Language
- Data Structures
- Design Patterns
- · Web Programming

- · Compiler Construction
- · Concurrent and Distributed Systems
- High Performance Computing
- Database Design

AWARDS

IASA IT ARCHITECTURE CORE (ITAC) - CITAF CERTIFICATION

IASA GLOBAL

Anchors to the beginning of Architect position and responsibilities

WON THE GIKI SOFTCOM 08 (PROGRAMMING COMPETITION)

GIKI UNIVERSITY PAKISTAN

A speed programming competition of national level

REFERENCES

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again.

- HEINRICH RUST

S As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders.

- PAUL FITZGERALD